// Array of questions
const questions = [
  {
    question: "Who is the current chess world champion?",
    answers: {
      a: "Magnus Carlsen",
      b: "Hikaru Nakamura",
      c: "Lady Gaga",
    },
    correctAnswer: "a",
  },
  {
    question: "Which two pieces are involved in castling?",
    answers: {
      a: "Carl and Robert",
      b: "Queen and Rook",
      c: "King and Rook",
    },
    correctAnswer: "c",
  },
  {
    question: "How many squares are on a chess board?",
    answers: {
      a: "2084",
      b: "64",
      c: "21",
    },
    correctAnswer: "b",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the winning move called?",
    answers: {
      a: "Checkmate",
      b: "Checkmark",
      c: "Shazam",
    },
    correctAnswer: "a",
  },
  {
    question: "What FIDE rating is required for the title Fide Master(FM)",
    answers: {
      a: "2200",
      b: "2300",
      c: "2400",
    },
    correctAnswer: "b",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the most popular response to 1.e4?",
    answers: {
      a: "e5",
      b: "e6",
      c: "c5",
    },
    correctAnswer: "c",
  },
  {
    question: "What is a draw?",
    answers: {
      a: "Checkmate",
      b: "Stalemate",
      c: "What's up mate",
    },
    correctAnswer: "b",
  },
  {
    question: "How many forms of castling are there?",
    answers: {
      a: "Short Castling",
      b: "Long Castling",
      c: "Both",
    },
    correctAnswer: "c",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the most popular first move?",
    answers: {
      a: "e4",
      b: "d4",
      c: "c4",
    },
    correctAnswer: "a",
  },
  {
    question: "What is a very bad move called in chess?",
    answers: {
      a: "Screw Up",
      b: "Mistake",
      c: "Blunder",
    },
    correctAnswer: "c",
  },
];
export { questions };
